Guide to the Time Inc. Life Editorial Records 1937-2013 MS 3009-RG 9
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Life Editorial Records
1937-2013
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 9
44 Linear feet in 41 record cartons, 2 flat boxes, and 1 microfilm box including 8 reels of microfilm
The Life Editorial Records include files from offices and staff that produced both the original version of Life and the revived monthly version.
Arrangement Note
Organized into ten series:
Series I. General Files
Series II. Managing Editor Files
Series III. Executive Editor Eleanor Graves Files
Series IV. Senior Editor Files
Series V. Staff Writer Dora Jane Hamblin Research Interviews for That Was the Life
Series VI. Photographer Alfred Eisenstaedt Files
Series VII. Letters Department Reports
Series VIII. Consent Releases
Series IX. John Loengard Interview Project Videotapes
Series X. Book Copy Files: LIFE: The Greatest Adventures of All Time
Historical Note
For the majority of Time Inc.'s existence, the company maintained a strict separation of editorial from the publishing and business side of each magazine, colloquially called the separation of "church" (editorial) and "state" (publishing). Editorial includes the editors, researchers, and art department. The editorial side reported up to the editor-in-chief and the publishing/business side reported up to the corporate business executive which was the president prior to 1960 and the chief executive officer after. Henry Luce structured Time Inc. this way so that the business side could not (in theory) influence the editorial content of the publications. For example, the advertising sales people could not interfere with a magazine's decision to run an article on the dangers of cigarette smoking, even though it might mean losing millions of dollars in tobacco ads.
Time Inc. published the first issue of Life on November 23, 1936. In the initial proposal to the board, the specifications were that it would be the same size as the Illustrated London News, printed on shiny paper with around 200 high-quality photographs recording significant current news events including detailed captions. Because the suggested price would be 10 cents per issue, the initial title was Dime, The Show-Book of the World. According to Elson, staff and charter subscribers were asked to submit other names, and the title Life was suggested by both cofounder Henry Luce's wife Clare Luce and Time Inc. president James Linen's father. Since the name was already in use by another publication, Luce purchased it in order to acquire the rights.
The first staff members in 1936 were Luce as managing editor with John Martin as an alternate, Daniel Longwell as picture editor, Alfred Eisenstaedt and Peter Stackpole as staff photographers, and Mary Fraser as copy chief.
For financial reasons, Time Inc. suspended production of Life as a weekly magazine in December 1972, but began planning a revival almost immediately. The Magazine Development department published the first Life special in 1973 as a newsstand magazine followed by nine more. Time Inc. revived Life as a monthly in 1978. In 2000, publication was again suspended, but revived in 2004 as a newspaper supplement. In 2007, Time Inc. completely ceased printing of Life and created a website for images from the collection.
Citations:
Elson, Robert T. 1968. Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1923-1941. New York: Atheneum.
Hooper, Bill. Email to Holly Deakyne, 10 June 2016.
Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. 1986. The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, 1960-1980. New York: Atheneum.
Time To Stop Publishing Life Magazine, Will Keep It Online. U.S. News. CNBC, 26 March 2007. https://www.cnbc.com/id/17797635.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials may include privileged attorney correspondence; personnel performance evaluations; contracts and agreements; and records with personally identifiable information. Restricted materials are located in boxes 2221-2225 and R38. Materials created within the past 35 years also may be subject to restriction on a case-by-case basis. Unreformatted audiovisual material in the collection is not accessible. This includes boxes 2197-2220, 2215, and 2226-2227. Except for microfilm, materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library. Early editorial materials may be in RG 1. Subject Files.
Scope and Contents Note
The Life Editorial Records include files from offices and staff that produced both the original version of Life and the revived monthly version. The Managing Editors (ME) begin with the last ME of the original Life. Other staff included are one Executive Editor; two Senior Editors, one from the original Life and one from the revived version; two staff photographers, with Alfred Eisenstaedt being one of the original hires at the launch of the magazine; and one staff writer. Records include business correspondence, interoffice memoranda, letters from readers, drafts of articles, audiovisual interviews and oral histories, article proposals, and magazine and corporate policies.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Astronauts -- United States.; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Journalists -- United States; Oral histories (document genres); Organization files; Photojournalists -- United States; Project Apollo (U.S.); Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Daniels, Judith; Eisenstaedt, Alfred; Farmer, Gene; Graves, Eleanor; Graves, Ralph; Hamblin, Dora Jane, 1920-1993; Kunhardt, Philip B.; Larsen, Jonathan; Loengard, John; Okrent, Daniel, 1948-; Ryan, Pat, 1938-2013; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I. General Files, 1967-1996, 2013; 231778; 0.5 Linear feet in 4 folders
  Arrangement
  Organized alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  General Files includes material about Life, but not specific to any department.
  - Compiled by the Time Inc. Archives, 1978-1996 (Offsite-box 2219, Folder 9-10)
    Includes "All Staff" memoranda, song lyrics, drafts of stories and magazine issues, magazine dummies, and event invitations.
  - Miniature Reprint of First Issue, undated (Offsite-box 2219, Folder 11)
  - 1967 Proof with Transferring Correspondence, 1967, 2013 (Offsite-box 2219, Folder 12)
- Series II.A. Managing Editor Ralph Graves Files, 1968-1973; 230169; 5 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
  Biographical Note
  Ralph Graves was a long-time reporter then Senior Staff Editor for Life before being appointed its managing editor in 1969. As Time Inc. suspended publication of Life in 1972, he was the last managing editor of the original Life. After the closure of Life, Graves held editorial positions at the corporate level. He retired from Time Inc. in 1983.
  Citations:
  Bonanos, Christopher. "Last Editor of Weekly Life Magazine Dies." Daily Intelligencer. New York, June 17, 2013. http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/06/last-editor-of-weekly-life-magazine-dies.html
  Scope and Contents Note
  Records includes correspondence and subject files from Ralph Graves during his tenure as Managing Editor of Life spanning from 1968 to 1973 documenting editorial content and story selection, background information on articles, and the publication process. Some files are from his prior position as Senior Staff Editor.
  The general correspondence contains primarily letters from readers including article suggestions and letters from children as school assignments; invitations; and some correspondence with other Time Inc. departments. Items of interest include an invitation from Roy Disney to attend the opening of Walt Disney World (1971); an advice request from an editor at Screw magazine (1971); and letters from Ray Bradbury offering poems on space exploration for publication (1970). The poems are no longer present and may have been moved to his Bio File in RG 2.
  It is unclear if the empty folders ever contained records, and if they were created by Grave's office or by the Time Inc. Archives.
  Arrangement Note
  Organized by year based on the original arrangement, and alphabetically within each year for ease of use. Undated empty folders were dated based on the folders originally surrounding them.
  - 1968 Files, 232185 (Offsite-box -)
  - Tito [empty], 1968; 232116 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 1)
  - 1969 Files, 232187 (Offsite-box -)
  - Advertisers by P.I.B. Classifications, 1969; 232118 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 2)
  - Advertising Staff [empty], 1969; 232119 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 3)
  - Alexander, Shana [empty], 1969; 232121 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 4)
  - Astronauts, 1969; 232122 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 5)
    Includes the script for motion picture Apollo! (Man & Space), and treatments and budgets for Life television specials.
  - Astronauts [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R38)
  - Beard, Peter, 1969; 232125 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 6)
  - Brennan, Hank, 1969; 232126 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 7)
  - Budget, 1969; 232128 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: General, 1969; 232129 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 9-11)
  - Correspondence: Staff, 1969; 232130 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 12)
  - Donovan, Hedley [empty], 1969; 232132 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 13)
  - Dowd, Jack, 1969; 232134 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 14)
  - Dubos, Rene [empty], 1969; 232135 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 15)
  - Editorial Services [empty], 1969; 232136 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 16)
  - Expo 70: Edit Staff Accomodations, 1969; 232137 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 17)
  - General Learning Corporation, 1969; 232139 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 18)
  - Graves, Ralph [empty], 1969; 232140 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 19)
  - Griffith, Tom [empty], 1969; 232142 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 20)
  - Hardy, Jerry [empty], 1969; 232143 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 21)
  - Harris, Louis, 1969; 232146 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 22-23)
  - Investigative Reporting, 1969; 232148 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 24)
  - Kirkland, Sally [empty], 1969; 232149 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 25)
  - Kunhardt, Phil, 1969; 232150 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 26)
  - Life Letters Log, 1969; 232152 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 27)
  - Life Letters Reports, 1969; 232153 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 28-30)
    Includes summaries of reader letters and lists of known errors.
  - Life and R. R. Donnelley Joint Committee, 1969; 232155 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 31)
    R.R. Donnelley & Sons Company is a printer.
  - Life International [empty], 1969; 232156 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 32)
  - Luce, Henry: The Ideas of Henry Luce, 1969; 232157 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 33)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1969; 232158 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 34)
  - Masthead, 1969; 232159 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 35)
  - Moon Book, 1969; 232160 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper Guild, 1969; 232161 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 37)
  - Nuclear Power Story [empty], 1969; 232162 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 38)
  - Office Space, 1969; 232163 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 39)
  - Photographers, 1969; 232164 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 40)
  - Production, 1969; 232165 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 41)
  - Project Olympia, 1969; 232166 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 42)
  - Promotion, 1969; 232167 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 43)
  - Regional Edit, Reviews [empty], 1969; 232168 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 44)
  - Santa Barbara Oil Story [empty], 1969; 232169 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 45)
  - Schedule of Issue, 1969; 232170 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 46)
  - Steed, Robert [empty], 1969; 232171 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 47)
  - Staff Memoranda, 1969; 232172 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 48)
  - Text Department, 1969; 232173 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 49)
  - Time-Life Books [empty], 1969; 232174 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 50)
  - Topic, 1969; 232175 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 51)
  - Trim Size [empty], 1969; 232176 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 52)
  - Whittemore, L. H., 1969; 232177 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 53)
  - Year-End Issue, 1969; 232178 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 54)
  - 1970 Files, 232188 (Offsite-box -)
  - Alcoa [empty], 1970; 232179 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 55)
  - Ardrey, Robert, 1970; 232180 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 56)
  - Astronauts, 1970; 232181 (Offsite-box 2201, Folder 57)
  - Budget, 1970; 232189 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 1)
  - Contract Writers, 1969-1970; 232190 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 2)
  - Contract Writers [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R38)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970; 232191 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 3-10)
  - Correspondence: Staff, 1970; 232192 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 11)
  - December 3 Dinner, 1970; 232193 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 12)
    Correspondence and planning for a dinner meeting with the editorial, reporting, and photography departments to discuss future stories.
  - Donovan, Hedley, 1970; 232194 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 13)
  - Dragadze, Peter [RESTRICTED], 1970 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Edit Planning [empty], 1970; 232195 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 14)
  - EVR [empty], 1970; 232196 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 15)
  - Farmer, Gene, 1970; 232197 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 16)
  - Gary, Romain, 1970; 232198 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 17)
  - Griffith, Tom [empty], 1970; 232199 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 18)
  - Hycon, 1970; 232200 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 19)
  - Investigative Reporting [empty], 1970; 232201 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 20)
  - Kantor, MacKinlay, 1970; 232202 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 21)
  - Kunhardt, Phil: My Father's House, 1970; 232203 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 22)
  - Leakey, Richard, 1970; 232204 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 23)
  - Leaves of Absence, 1970; 232205 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 24)
  - Life Letters Reports, 1970; 232206 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 25-27)
  - Life International, 1970; 232207 (Offsite-box 2202, Folder 28)
  - Mackland, Ray, 1970; 232294 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 1)
  - Mock-ups, 1970; 232295 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Guild, 1970; 232296 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 3)
  - Parting Shots [empty], 1970; 232297 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 4)
  - Photographers, 1970; 232298 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 5)
  - Private Lives Articles, 1970; 232299 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 6)
  - Production: Cost Schedules, 1970; 232300 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 7)
  - Report: College Student Attitudes, 1970; 232301 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 8)
  - Report: Youth Attitudes, 1970; 232302 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 9)
  - Rockefeller Cousins Article, 1970; 232303 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 10)
  - Sesame Street/Children's Television Workshop, 1970; 232304 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 11-13)
    Contains records regarding Life planning to run educational content such as "puzzles, games, letters, activities." Materials include the proposal creating the Children's Television Workshop and the proposal to continue Sesame Street for a second year.
  - Special Sections [empty], 1970; 232305 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 14)
  - Staff Book Agreements [RESTRICTED], 1970 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Staff Memoranda, 1970; 232306 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 15)
  - Subpoena [empty], 1970; 232307 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 16)
  - Supplements, 1970; 232308 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 17)
  - Themes, 1970; 232309 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 18)
  - Time-Life Books, 1970; 232310 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 19)
  - Valk, Gary, 1970; 232311 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 20)
  - Veterans Administration, 1970; 232312 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 21)
  - Vietnam Revisited [empty], 1970; 232314 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 22)
  - Year-End Issue, 1970; 232315 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 23)
  - Year-End and Double Issues [empty], 1970; 232316 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 24)
  - 1971 Files, 232317 (Offsite-box -)
  - Advertising Lunches and Meetings, 1971; 232318 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 25)
  - Armstrong-Jones, Anthony, 1971; 232319 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 26)
  - Betty Grissom Article, 1971; 232320 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 27)
  - Budget, 1971; 232321 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 28)
  - Circulation, 1971; 232322 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: General, 1971; 232323 (Offsite-box 2203, Folder 30-36)
  - Correspondence: Staff, 1971; 232324 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 1)
  - Donovan, Hedley, 1971; 232325 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 2)
  - Howard Hughes Article, 1971; 232326 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 3)
  - Legal Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 1971 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Life Letters Reports, 1971; 232327 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 4-6)
  - Look Magazine, 1971; 232328 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 7)
  - Mailer, Norman: Lunch, 1971; 232329 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 8)
  - Masthead (Donovan File), 1971; 232330 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 9)
  - Mock-ups, 1971; 232331 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 10)
  - Mok, Mike [RESTRICTED], 1971 (Offsite-box R38)
  - National Alcoholic Beverage Control Association Conference, 1971; 232332 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 11)
  - Parting Shots, 1971; 232333 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 12)
  - Personnel: Headhunt, 1971; 232335 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 13)
  - Photo Contest, 1971; 232336 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 14)
  - Plimpton, George, 1971; 232334 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 15)
  - Production, 1971; 232337 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 16)
  - Professional Photographers of American Convention, 1971; 232338 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 17)
  - Public Access Television Report, 1971; 232339 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 18)
  - Snow, Edgar, 1971; 232340 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 19)
  - Staff Memoranda, 1971; 232341 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 20)
  - Supplements, 1971; 232342 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 21)
  - Syndication, 1971; 232343 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 22-23)
  - 1972 Files, 232344 (Offsite-box -)
  - Audience, 1972; 232346 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 24)
  - Budget, 1972; 232347 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: General, 1972; 232348 (Offsite-box 2204, Folder 26-28)
  - Correspondence: General, 1972; 232349 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 1-3)
    Folder 4 of 6 includes a letter from Jim Gaines, later Life Managing Editor, prior to his employment with Time Inc. and correspondence regarding the Guy Richards project.
  - Correspondence: Record of Correspondence to Graves, 1972; 232350 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence: Staff, 1972; 232351 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 6)
  - Headcount, 1972; 232352 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 7)
  - Hesburgh, Theodore: "America's Unfinished Human Agenda", 1972; 232353 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 8)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1972; 232354 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 9)
  - Maness, Dave, 1972; 232355 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 10)
  - Maness, Dave [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Mock-ups, 1972; 232356 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 11)
  - Myerson, Bess, 1972; 232357 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Guild, 1972; 232358 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 13-14)
    Includes meeting minutes.
  - Olympics, 1972; 232359 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 15)
  - Personnel: Benefits, 1972; 232360 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 16)
  - Personnel: Life Edit, 1972; 232361 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 17)
  - Production, 1972; 232362 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 18)
  - Richards, Guy: Project, 1972; 232363 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 19-20)
  - Romanoff, A.N.: Threatened Lawsuit, 1972; 232364 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 21)
  - Simon, Norton, 1972; 232365 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 22)
  - Staff Memoranda, 1972; 232366 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 23)
  - Story Inventory and Disposal, 1972; 232367 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 24)
  - Torres, Jose, 1972; 232368 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 25)
  - Valk, Garry [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Offsite-box R38)
  - 1973 Files, 232369 (Offsite-box -)
  - Budget, 1973; 232370 (Offsite-box 2205, Folder 26)
- Series II.B. Managing Editor Philip Kunhardt Files, 1978-1982; 231770; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  According to his biography released by Corporate Public Affairs, Philip Kunhardt joined Life as a reporter in 1950 and rose to Assistant Managing Editor in 1962. After the closure of Life in 1972, Kunhardt worked in Magazine Development designing new potential publications such as Camera Month, Woman, and People. He also was editor for the Life Special Reports. Kunhardt was named Life Managing Editor when it was revived as a monthly in 1978. He retired from Time Inc. in 1982 and later founded Kunhardt Productions.
  Fox, Margalit. "Philip B. Kunhardt Jr., 78, Writer and Producer of Documentaries, Is Dead." New York Times, March 24, 2006. https://www.nytimes.com/2006/03/24/arts/philip-b-kunhardt-jr-78-writer-and-producer-of-documentaries-is-dead.html.
  Records includes correspondence and subject files from Philip Kunhardt during his tenure as Managing Editor of Life from 1978 to 1982.
  Organized into two series:
  II.B.1. Correspondence
  II.B.2. Subject Files
  - Subseries II.B.1. Correspondence, 1980-1982; 232494; 1.5 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Correspondence includes invitations to speak or attend professional events; letters from readers, writers, and photographers; article proposals; photograph offers; and requests for copies of photographs.
    Organized alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent.
    - Correspondence: A-S, 1980-1982; 232484 (Offsite-box 2206)
    - Correspondence: T-Z, 1980-1982; 232487 (Offsite-box 2206, Folder 1-5)
  - Subseries II.B.2. Subject Files, 1978-1982; 232497; 0.5 Linear feet in 6 folders
    The Subject Files are dominated by records on the published interview of convict Bernard Welch, the resulting controvery over payment to him for photographs, and the complaint filed by the National News Council against Life.
    - Assignment Letters, 1978-1982; 232488 (Offsite-box 2206, Folder 6)
    - Halberstam/Welch Article, 1981; 232489 (Offsite-box 2206, Folder 7-10)
    - National News Council: In the Public Interest, 1975-1979; 232499 (Offsite-box 2206, Folder 11)
- Series II.C. Managing Editor Judith Daniels Files, 1982-1987; 231771; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Biographical/Historical Note
  Prior to joining Time Inc., Judith "Judy" Daniels served as a managing editor at New York magazine and The Village Voice, was a founder of Women's Media Group, and was founder and Editor-in-Chief of Savvy, the first major magazine for executive women. She joined Time Inc. in 1982 and was named Life Managing Editor that same year, serving through April 1987. After leaving Time Inc., she held editorial positions at Condé Nast Publications.
  Citation:
  Fox, Margalit. "Judith Daniels, Editor of Savvy Magazine, Dies at 74." The New York Times, September 4, 2013. https://www.nytimes.com/2013/09/05/business/media/judith-daniels-74-editor-of-savvy-magazine-dies.html
  Records includes correspondence and subject files from Judy Daniels during her tenure as Managing Editor of Life spanning from 1982 to 1987
  The majority of files are her chrono files and correspondence containing letters from readers; article suggestions; invitations to professional events; intraoffice discussion of articles; complaints from the subjects of articles; and requests to phtograph events.
  Some subject files that may be hers are in the Managing Editor General Files.
  Organized alphabetically based on the original arrangement.
  - Chrono File, 1985-1986; 232518 (Offsite-box 2207, Folder 12-16)
  - Corporate Memoranda: General, 1985; 232519 (Offsite-box 2207, Folder 17)
  - Corporate Memoranda: Benefits, 1985; 232520 (Offsite-box 2208, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1987; 232521 (Offsite-box 2208, Folder 2-30)
  - Stringers: Best Suggestions, 1982-1983; 232522 (Offsite-box 2208, Folder 31)
  - Stringers: Life, 1985; 232523 (Offsite-box 2208, Folder 32)